<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-16th-amendment</id>
    <results>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1909-10-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=sixteenth+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Sixteenth Amendment
The Constitution of the Unit
ed StAtfls was mimnsplv maAo Aif
icultj to amend. Madison, the
'Father of the Constitution,' was
against ''innovation' and Hamil-'
ton' feared the turbulent, chan-'
ging people. So the Constitution'
was made unchangeable except b.
a vote of two-thirds of Congress,
and three-fourths of the State
Legislatures or State Conventions.
One-forty-fourth df the voters to- j
day, if prperly placoed, can block'
any amendment. Of the four,
hundred and thirty-five amend-'
wents proposed from 1889 to 1904'
noi one was aaopteu. it is tne
belief of many people that the;
Constitution can never be amend-'
ed. I
"We, on 'the other hand, believe
Amendment permiting the income1
tax, is possible, probable, inevita-'
cle. The- resolution was. -unani-j
mously adopted by the Senate,
and. almost unanimously by the
House. Thirty-five of the forty
six States must ratify, but thirty-five
States will be found. The
South is for it; the west is for
it; the real people of the East
are for it; the two parties have
declared in. its favor and Presi
dent Taft has taken his stand on
it. It is more than the mere
question of an income tax, al
though that is important. It is a
question of national sovereignty,
of the right of ninety millions of
petTple to tax. themselves as they
deem just and expedient. It is
an issue upon which in times of
danger the national welfare, ev
en the national existence, might
depend. The Sixteenth Amend
ment nnist and will be adopted.
But it will not be adopted by
the people staying at. home and
wishing for it. It must be made
an issue in every 'State, in every
assembly district. Time fights
on the side of the Sixteenth
Amendment; there is no limit.
Once a State adopts it, the rati
fication lasts' forever. But if
the ratification is not made the
first session, H may be again pro-,
posed for 'the second, third,
tenth, or ninety-ninth time. If iwe
do not suceed at first,, we can
j try, try again.
I The Sixteenth Amendment
must be ratfiied, not only to en
able pur Government in times of
peace and war to impose equita-.
ble taxes, but also to place the
fundamental law of the land,
where it should be placed in the
hands of an intelligent, tolerant,
and liberty-loving, people.</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1912-03-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>This Resolution and Another
Providing for Ratification
of Income Tax Amend
ment Will Be Rushed
Through
There was nothing tn it yesterday
but unless somebody spikes the guns
before 1 -o'clock today the hair-raising
stunts will begin and before sundown
every judge in the state of Arizona
and every man who has a few dollars
:md sixty cents will have license to
tremble in his shoes, if he is at ail
nervous in his temperament. Rules
have been adopted sufficient for the
legal transaction of legislative busi
ness and as soon as the decks are
cleared for action this morning a
concurrent resolution will be intro
duced in both houses., submitting to
the people an amendment to the con
stitution providing for the recall of
judges, and it will be passed quicker
than either President Taft or the
proletariat can say Jack Robinson.
.Colore the smoke clears away a joint
resolution will drift in. to the effect
that Arizona endorses the proposed
sixteenth amendment to the constitu
tion of the United States, providing
for an income tax. Thirty-one states
have already endorsed it and only five
more are needed. There will be one
less today and the time has arrived
for the plutocrats to throw up their
hands, or at least stand up and be
counted.</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042373/1913-02-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>March. The tax
itself In its provision and limita
tions is left to congress. Con
gressional leaders, who havo been
IfM"*
for U,e flnal
ratification
by the states, estimate that the
Income tax would bring the gov
vcar,Cnt
about
"00,000,000 a
the tax ls provided by
the constitution, the proposed ex
cise tax, framed by the democra
tic leaders ln 1912 to meet the
Sic"HPt* decision which
nelcl the former Incomc tax un
itwtlonal, will be dropped.
®f its provisions may be
Included in the new law.
Sixteenth Amendment.
Washington. Feb. 3.—The provi
sion authorizing an income tax as now
i?nnen.?nP£rtknown
.of
the federal
constitu­
tion will be as the "Sixteenth
Amendment" and reads as follows:
Article XVI.—The congress shall
have power to lay and collect taxes on
incomes, from whatever source de-
w'",ou'
apportionment among
the states, and without regard to any
census or enumeration."</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1913-02-06/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>After Four Years Wait Enough
States Approved Sixteenth
Amendment.
Fiercest of the Assaults Are
Very Much Disturbed In The
Miss Lydakl Garnett Becomes
Bride Of Mr. Hugh W.
Linton.
School Boys Will Stampede
Directed Against the Fork
HendersonHJistrict
Lately.
Suffragette Parade In
Novel Way.
ress of Adrianople.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038161/1913-02-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Sixteenth Amendment.
The Sixteenth Amendment to the constitution of the United
States has been ratified by the legislatures of thirty eight states,
two more than the required three-fourths. It gives Congress the
power "to lay and collect taxes on incomes, from whatever source
derived, without apportionment among the several states, and with
out regard to any census or enumeration."
Congress having been given this power what is its duty We
believe that it should at once proceed to pass an income tax law,
Some argue that no such duty devolves upon Congress that the
amendment simply gives congress the power to act but that it does
not follow that it should act at once as present conditions do not
demand such action and the provision is solely for the purpose of
giving congress the power to pass a law when the necessity shall
arise.
As viewed in the light of history, is this argument good We
think not. The Sixteenth Amendment is the only amendment to
the constitution in forty three years. In 1893 Congress passed an
income tax law which the Supreme Court held unconstitutional.
For this reason those favoring an income tax law proposed amend
ing the constitution. Finally in 1909 both houses of Congress by a
three-fourths vote passed the proposed amendment and now three
fourths of the states by their legislatures have ratified it.
Since a few years after the close of the Civil War, there has been
practically as much need for an income tax at one time as another.
The members of Congress believed that the people wanted this law
or- they never would have passed the amendment, as most of them
were voting to impose a tax upon their own incomes. The members
of the state legislatures that ratified it also thought that the people
wanted it or they would not have voted for it, because it is not the
type of measure that is passed by a legislature against the wishes
of the people.
The people believe that an income tax is fair and just and Con
gress should pass one at once. We can see no reason why one
should not be passed. It is only right that the people who are re
ceiving the largest benefits from government should pay for keep
ing it up that those who can best afford to pay for maintaining the
government should do so. A person's income is the best gauge of
his ability to pay. An income tax it is hoped and believed will take
some of the burden of the support and maintenance of the govern
ment off of the shoulders of the poor and put it on the shoulders of
the rich, where we believe it belongs.
But it's opponents says that it will make a nation of liars. If
a man will lie about his income to prevent paying a tax on it, he is
already lying about how much property he has to prevent paying a
tax on it. It is not making a liar out of him, because he was already
one.
It's opponents also say that it will be unjust, as incomes derived
from certain sources are much more definitely determined than
from others that the man on a salary will almost certainly pay</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1915-09-25/ed-1/?sp=8&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>INCOME TAX LAW
AGAIN ATTACKED.
Washington, Sept. 23. Counsel
for Union Pacific Railroad stock
holders and others have filed a brief
in the Supreme Court attacking as
unconstitutional the income tax
provisions of the Underwood-Simmons
tariff law.
The attorneys contend that while
the sixteenth amendment empowers
congress to impose a tax on "incomes
from whatever source derived," the
framers of the law stretched it to
cover many taxes other than on in
come. It is asserted, too, that there is no
constitutional authority for taxing a
specific class of persons, unmarried
men, more than others, or for the
super-tax imposed upon men with
incomes over $20,000.
Old newspapers for sale here.
SUPREME COURT TO
PASS ON GAME LAW</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1915-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Washington, D. C., Oct. 13.—An an
nual revenue to the government of
$82,000,000 depends on the outcome of
arguments today before the supreme
court on the constitutionality of the
income tax. The first cases to reach
the court under the new system of fed
eral taxation and the first Involving
the construction of the sixteenth
amendment were at issue.
Attacking the law were corporations
objecting to the law in part and as an
entirety mining companies voicing
objections to the tax on mining In
come and individuals, attacking prin
cipally the additional tax on incomes
in excess of $20,000. The main de
fense of the law has been prepared by
the government.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84031081/1916-01-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HANDS DOWN OPINION
Sixteenth Amendment to Con-j
stitution construed in Unan
imous Decision of Far
reaching Effect,
today a request that a United States receiving a majority In a state would
lie certified to congress to receive as
many votes as the state, has senators
and representatives. The house
soldier named .Harrison be punished
for hovlng fired on and wounded a
Mexican civilian late Saturday nfter
nnon. At the same time representa
tions to 55. L. Cobb, United States cus
toms collector here, were made that
American cattle thleve.H were stealing case of no majority the house would
cattle from Mexican owners south of elect a president from the three, can
die border. A demand wan made that diddles receiving tin: higher number
the thieves be apprehended and pun- of votes.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064057/1916-01-29/ed-1/?sp=2&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Washington -The income tax was
declared constitutional Monday by the
tion which swept aside every conttn
tion riisieti agatinst it and, in the api
itli of 'Ocll rs' aional leaders, opened
the way for increasing the tax rat- on
great fortunes to help pay for nati,,n
alt defense.
The decision was rannounced by
Chief Justice Whitn and was unani
of Ferank i. lrushaber from the ac
tion of thi Ne York fte eral court
in refusing to enjoin the Southern Pa
cific, of which Irusohaber was a stock
holder, from payning the tax. The
case raised substantially every point
involved in all the five income tax
allowing mining corporations to make
a 5 per cent deduction annually from
gross income for depletion of mines.
an amendment to the old corporation
tax, rather than a feature of the in
come tax.
The basic error of those who at
tacked the constitutionality of the
tax, Chief Justice White held, was in
regarding the sixteenth amendment as
ia direct tax without apportionment
tion. In fsubstance, thoe court held the at
the sixteenth amendment had not em
potereod the federal overnment tao
levy a new taxe out that "the whole
purpose of the amed ofment was to re-v
alieve all inco me taxes froain a consid
ieratherion of the aso rcfet whe nce the in
come was derived."</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1920-03-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ustices Holmes, Day, Iirandeis
hnd f'lark dl*s?\nted.
"A stock dividend representing
profits is income, no matter what the
condition, in the opinion of lawyers,
business men, bankers." said .lustice
Rrandels. "It has been held Income
by courts in California, in New York,
In dissenting States. Massachusetts
is one State In which n stock divi
dend was not held income."
Justice I'ittiey said:
"From every point of view, we are
brought Irresistjbly to, the conclu
sion that neither under the sixteenth
amendment nor otherwise lias Con
gress power to tax without appor
tionment a true stock dividend made
lawfully and In good faith, or the ac
cumulation of profits behind It. as
Income of the stockholder. The rev?
nu<- act of 191(1, Insofar as It Imposes
a tax upon the stockholder, because
of such dividend, violates the pro
visions of Article 1, section 2,
clause n, and Article I, section 0,
elouse 4, of the Constitution and to
this extent is Invalid notwithstand
ing the sixteenth amendment.
WAGE CONFERENCE S?T.
Walker D. lllnes, director general
of the Railroad Administration, to
day announced that the hi partisan
conference of railroad employes and
executives on wage demands has bean
definitely set fo% Wednesday.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030273/1920-03-09/ed-1/?sp=3&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax&st=text&r=-0.251,-0.075,1.502,1.502,0</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text>Koprescntatlve Hull (Tenn.) said the
decision gavo rich corporations and
stockholders opportunity of evading tax
ation to a large extent and throwing
the hurden on the poor people and made
possible the evasion of hundreds of mill
ions nf taxes. With tho declaration by
the court that taxation of stock divi
dends Is unconstitutional, notwithstand
ing tho Sixteenth Amendment, Congress
leaders doubted If there was any legis
lative step now by which the same pur
pose could be effected. Likewise It was
feared that aConstltutlonnl amendment
on the point might not etand.
The case just decided was appealed
to the Supreme Court 'by the Government
after Myrtle H. Macomber obtained a
similar decision from tho Federal Dis
trict Court for tho Southern District of
New York. Lai go financial Interests
made a test of tho case and employed
Charles E. Hughes as chtet counsel. The
In- i i r 'i</text>
      </result>



    </results>
  </topic>









  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-19th-amendment</id>
    <results>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1890-03-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Discussing+suffrage</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Dunncll of Minnesota was inclined to vote
against the bill on account of the woman suffrage
clause
Washington of Tennessee attacked tho
womans suffrage clause and held the people of
Wyoming had violated the provision of the act
of organization limiting the suffrage to white
male suffrage Women might be sent from
Wyoming to the Senate
E B Taylor of Ohio Dont you think that to
put good women Into the Senate might help it
some Laughter
Washington the gentleman himself were
In the Senate I might admit his proposition
Kerr of Iowa thought the opponents the
bill in bad straits whon they fell back for objec
tion upon the womans suffrage provision
Kelly of Kansas said he would not be
frightened i women had a seat on the floor of
the House and perhaps it would result in
benefit</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1895-05-21/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Womans+Congress+Pacific+Coast&st=text&r=-0.244,-0.059,1.489,1.489,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The president's table was a mass of fra
grant crimson roses, in the midst of which
was placed a marble statuette of the fa
mous Lucretia Mott. Susan ±5. Anthony's
seat had been made almost as gorgeous as
a regal throne. It was an antique, high
backed chair, which the ladies had dsaped
with old gold plush and wreathed with
yellow marguerites, tied with orange rib
bons the suffrage color.
Flowers were everywhere on the plat
form. Suspended from the ceiling,
"Woman's Congress, 1895." could be read
in large floral letters, and the left side of
the platform was entirely banked up with
an immense floral tribute which an anony
mous friend had sent to the president.
Ana Susan B. Anthony herself, the
grand old woman of woman's rights, the
evangel of the new woman, as new as she
beamed upon the welcoming faces before
her as the newest woman of them all.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1916-11-11/ed-1/?sp=6&q=JEANNETTE+RANKIN</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WONDER-WOMAN" IS MISffJEANNETTE RANKIN;
WILL BE FIRST OP SEX TO SIT IN CONGRESS
"Analytic and Energet
ic" Characterization
of Suffrage Leader
Who Is Likely to Add
M. C. to Name
What America's First Woman
Congressman Stands Fpr
NATIONAL womnn suffrage.
Protection of childhood.
Stato nnd national prohibition.
Farm loan law.
Equal taxation.
By LISETTA NEUKOM
MODESTY marks tho expression of the
woman who Is America's first fcml
nlno "Congress oman," Miss Jeannette Han
kin, of MlHsoula, Mont., to whom returns
today give the seat In Congress from Mon
tana Although she defeated seven men In the
primaries for the placo by a plurality of
7000, nnd will receive J7B0O a year salary
when she takes her seat In Congress, but
gives all to the women of Montana.
1 nm going to Washington to represent
tho women and children of tho West to
work for nn eight-hour day for women nnd
for laws providing that women shall be paid
tho same wuges as men for equal amounts
of work."</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1917-09-04/ed-1/?sp=3&q=SUFFRAGE+BANNER</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SUFFRAGE BANNER
BEARERS NABBED
Ten Women Arrested in Demon
stration in Front of White
Hpuse
Tlio Army mitt Nnvy Uu&IncMt Men's
Commltteo of tlie l'ocket Testament I.engue
liclil a meotliiK nt tlie City Club today to
niako plain for u Ms c.imimlKii to raise
money to provide Folillera of the National
Army, National (luatil vinltn recently taken
Into tlio regular urmy, regulars and unllora
with pocket Testaments.
J, Lewis Tuaddell, of tlio Itlttenliousc
Trust Company, Wlthcrspoon Uulldlng, was
appointed treasurer of the committee and
will take caro of tlio funds contributed here.
Otheis active In tlio movement were Joseph
JI Steele, who headed the organization which
conducted the Billy Sunday campaign Jiero.
nd J. Herbert Jefferles. George H. Davis,
Tho has worked win unaries 31. ieanuer,
originator of the movement, attended the
meeting with Mr Alexander nnd then left
nt onro for Chicago to place the plan before
the International Sunday School commit
tee, wh'ch represents nearly all churchc.
jr Inv... 1q" ql''1 '""t</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1917-11-12/ed-1/?sp=2&q=forty-one+arrested&st=text&r=-0.209,-0.071,1.419,1.419,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The forty-one women arrested last Satur
day afternoon for picketing the White
House In behalf of suffrage were found
guilty In police court this afternoon. Judge
Mullowncy did not sentence thft'wpmen. but
took the case under advisement and said he
would give It "deep consideration" before
making the sentences known.
Three women from Philadelphia Mrs.
Lawrence Lewis, Miss Kllznheth McShano
and Miss Cntharlne Lincoln were nrnong
those found guilty.
Attorneys for .Mrs. Harvey Wiley, wife
of the pure food specialist, gave notice of nn
appeal nnd she ws released tinder $100
bond. The others, among wheni are Mr?.
John Winters Ilrannan. social leader or New
York, and Mrs. William Kent, wife of tin
former California Congressman, were re
leased under the $1025 collateral put up by
Miss Mary Ingham, 'if Philadelphia when
they were arrested Saturday.
The suffragists were arraigned In Court
In groups of fours, sixes nnd eights. Just
as they marched In different croups to the
White Houlie Saturday, nnd lifter each
group wbh tried and found guilty they were
asked by Judge Mullowney to step aside
until nil forty-one had been tried, when lie
said he would pronounce sentence
Hy hie careful questioning of each of the
prisoners ns to whether they had been nr
rested and sentenced heforo for n similar
orfense, It was plain that Judgo Mullowney
Intended to give "repeaters" n sentence of
perhaps six months and first-offenders only
thirty days In Jail.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-08-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Suffrage+Ratification</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Tennessee's Ratification
Gives 9,500,000 More
Right to Vote for Next
President in the Fall
Fight Begun in 1848
Campaign Opened in Seneca
Falls Started Movement
Which Enveloped World
Woman suffrage was won for the
women of all the states in the Union
when Tennessee, th'e thirty-sixth state,
ratified the Federal amendment. Ap?
proximately 27,000,000 women will be
entitled to vote in the Presidential
election this fall. State suffrage al?
ready ha^l enfranchised 17.500,000, and
ratification adds to this number 9,500,
000.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066315/1920-08-26/ed-1/?sp=1&q=WOMENS+RIGHT+VOTE&r=-0.451,0.34,1.557,0.929,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The right
of women to vote became a part of
the Constitution of the United States
here today when Secretary ot State.
Colby proclaimed the Nineteenth
Amendment a part ot the Constitution.
The proclamation was signed early
this morning at the home ot the Sec
retary. It had been prepared last
night
Suffrage leaders were summoned to
the State Department as soon tk.
proclamation was signed and notified
of the action. They cheered wildly
when they were told that the amend.
ment had been made operative. They
naa been expecting a public ceremony
however, and seemed to be quite dis
appointed when they learned that
there would be none. Theyasked
for a repeating of the ceremony in or
der that moving pictures could be tak.
en and that suffrage leaders could take
part in the ceremony. Colby replied
that he would consider the matter and
reUred to his private office. The suf
frage leaders then held a Jubilee at
heir headquarters. Miss Alice Paul
announced that they would not relax
their vigilance In the least to see that
the women of the country did not lose
the right which they have recently
won.</text>
      </result>



</topic>







  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-1884-presidential-election</id>
    <results>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1884-07-09/ed-1/?sp=1&q=FIRST+VOTE+TAKEN+Delegation+Protests+Grover+Cleveland+Hendricks+Palmer+House&r=-0.324,0.479,1.231,0.735,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHICAGO July 8 Driven t bay by the ao
tlon 01 tho New York delegation yesterday af
ternoon the antiCleveland mon Blrded them
elres for a fight over tbe unit rule Delegate
States visited Mr Kellys
from twcntr even Statl vllltod Kolbl
headquarters late at night b Invitation He
received assurances of support In such a fight
from all quarters An efforts to effect a
union on some prominent whoolhorso against
Cleveland failed The line between the Mo
Donald and the Randall men wo too strongly
drawn arard was more accoptable to the
West but Pennsylvania Indicated preference i
for Cleveland It the Randall column should
break T lll said to have been the effect ot
Bill Scotts missionary work Without Penn
yhanla no combination could b made with a
prospect of success
In this dilemma the only thing to do seemed
t b to attack the unit rule and trust to cir
cumstances If the attack was successful Gen
Butler Oov Hendrlcks Senator Voorhees
Oen John M Palmer William It Morrison
and other prominent statesmen hold Inter
views with Mr Kelly but the crowd In the
Palmer House was so groat that It wns difficult
with It after midnight</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045789/1884-07-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=WHO+SHALL+Chicago+Democrats+Grover+Cleveland+Hendricks+Convention&st=text&r=-0.216,-0.072,1.432,1.432,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Of the Democrats Assembled in
Convention at Chicago.
The Cleveland Men Claim That
His Nomination
Can be Made on the First
Second Ballot,
or
While Thurman's Followers are
Confident of His Success.
Indiana Will Stick Solidly to
McDonald.
Cochran or do one else could be allow-'
ed to speak unless to present the name
of a candidate. Cockran replied that
he was there to second the nomination
of Judge Thurman and he wns allow
ed to proceed in mucn contusion, lie
said he was too warm friend of Cleve
land's to want to see him
subjected to the humiliation of defeat
which was greeted with laughter and
confusion. Cochran maintained furth
er that Thurman was the man who
only could unite and lead the grand
old" party of Jackson on to victory.
Portions of his speech were well re
ceived and frequently applauded.
lie closed by saying that
some of the members of the cou
vcutiou thought that Cleveland could
carry the country, while others
thought that he could not. One side
or the other must be wrong, then why
take finv chances when all could unite
ou the old wheel-horse Thurman.
Another motion was made to sus
pend the order of business for a recess,
which was amended to a motion to
adjourn, and on a call of the roll of
states the conventional 6:20 adjourned
until 10:30 a. m. to-morrow.
at 6:30 p. m. the rules were suspende
and a reces9 taken till 10:30 to-morrow
morning.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053573/1884-07-12/ed-1/?sp=1&q=CLEVELAND+WINS+Grover+Hendricks+Democratic+Convention+Chicago</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A delegate from Pennsylvania moved that
the convention now proceed to a second bal
lot. Ordered.
Then Mr. Snowdcn, of Pennsylvania, with
thanks to thoo who had voted for Samuel J.
Randall, withdrew that gentleman's name
The second ballot commenced at 11:20, with
tho following result
Alabama gavo for Bayard H cheers, Mc
Donald 1, Cleveland S. Arkansas Cleveland
14 tchecrs. Calltomla Thurman 18. Colo
radoCleveland 6. Connecticut Clovcland
1Z Delaware Bayard 6. .Florida Clovcland
Bayard 2. Georgia Clovcland 14, Bay
rd 10.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053573/1884-11-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=RESU</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Mr. Blalno is suro of tho vote of Oregon
pd Colorado, and almost as suro of Call
amis and Nevada. Those fonr states will
bring bts total to 133, and ho will bat
need to secaro IS votes from tho flvo
oloio states to insuro his election. At
this writing his chanco of securing any
one of them, or all of them, appears to bo
fully as good is that of his opponent.
TEW YOKK.
Brooklyn, Not. 4. Considerable delay Is
caused by tho canvass or tho constitutional
amendment and the state Judiciary, which the
board of electors insisted snould be canvaisod
Immediately after the electoral ticket.
New York, Nov. 4. 8:31 p. M. The repub
lican national commtttco privately conceded
New York' state to Cleveland by 0,1X10 ma
jority. This estimate was based on .returns
from cities. During- the next hour's returns
Irom less populous districts 'mado a consider
able decreaso In that estlmato. Therdomo.
fTAtlt national committee claim tho state br
from GO.OOO to 100,000. This estimate claims
Kings county by 18.000, Queens by 0,000; and
ltlchmond, all official, by '4000.
Elmira, Nor. 4. This city gives Blalno a
gain of 654 over Garfield.
Chemung couuty will give Blalno 400 ma
jority. IJtub (dem.) la elected assemblyman,
and Arnot (dein.) to congress.
Salamanca, N. Y., Nov. 4. Cattaraugus
county will Rive 1,500 for Blaine. Both repub
lican assemblymen will bo elected, and also
tbe member of congress.
AUBURN, N. Y Nov. 4. Eight wards of this
city give 1,010 republican plurality; estimating
two wards tbe plurality will be 1,200.
ESYRACVSE, tfOV.S. 11113 City COmpiCIO
;lvcs Blalno a majority of 1,819.
Utica, N. Y., Nov. 4, This city, complete,
elves Blalno a majority of 1,819.
elves about 400 malorltv for Cleveland.
Johnstown, N. Y Nov. 4. Tho majority for
Sll, ln 1."..lln MA. f HA Tk. II
iJI&IIIVlU rUllUUVUUUIJI19t,WV, lun ii.-juuii-
can majority for member of congress Is nbout
700. The republican asseinblyniuu is elected.
Albany, N. Y Nov. 4. Finder (dem.) for
congress has about 1,700 majority in Schoharlo
and Clevuland about l,bO0. It is probablu that
the democratic majority In Albany county will
bo leas than 1,600. Tho democrats concede the
election of Swinburne (rep.) to congress.
Buffalo, Nov. 4. 'Iho election hero was
generally very quiet, although a largo vote has
been polled; the largest for years. With three
strong democratic dlslrlctstobear from, which
will probably give Cleveland 400 majority,
and two republican districts to hear from,
which will probably add to Blaine's majority
by 200, Blalno has carried tho city by 1,089.
l.ockwood (dciu.), congressional candidate, is
lefeatcd by over 1,200 by Col. Farquhar.
John B. Weber Is elocted probably by a small
majority for congress in tbe thirty-third dis
trict. In Cleveland's own ward Blalno has a
majority over Cleveland ot 299. This ward as
a rule Is 700 republican majority.
Tho vote for Butler In tho city will foot up
about 123, und for St. John about 310. The
votes arc tlrst being counted tor the heads of
tickets. The assembly districts are comttig In
very slowly.
Lancaster, which Is usually a closely con
tested town, gives Cleveland 100 majority.
New Yorh, Nov. 4. Tho following tulvgiams
havo been received</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014381/1884-11-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=CONTEST+RESULT+DOUBT+Grover+Cleveland+Hendricks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MotrraoHKitY, November Ith.— Montgomery
•ity gives 560 majority tor Blame. Scattering
returns from different quarters show that
Cleveland will carry the Suite by a large major
ity. Jones for Congress in the First District,
Herbert in the Second, Oates in the Third, Car
tel in the Fifth, Martin in the Sixth ainJ Forney
in the Seventh all Democrats— arc certainly
•lecved.
COLORADO.
Pkwkr, November ith. Besides the Presi
dential Electors and one Congressman ;i full list
•f .Stalo officers will be elected to-day.
CONNECTICUT.
Xkw Haven, November 4th.— A veryheavj
Tote was polled early. The Independents arc
voting largely and mainly the entire Demo
cratic tiekel. The ISutlor, Irish-Blame and Pro
hibition vote is insignificant
llAßTptii:i>. November ith. Hartford gives
Cleveland 5,234, Blame 4,512. Cleveland's plu
rality, 721.
lIAKTVDiin, November ith. Thirty towns give
Slaiue 7,130, Cleveland, T.i'.l, Garfield 7.7>i'>.
Hancock 7,166. For Governor, Harrison 7,247,
Waller 7. "is. scattering 121. The same towns in
1882 gave Butler 5,438, Waller 6,304, scattering
301. In the First District Buck is probably
sleeved to Congress.
Hartriki), November Ith. Seventy-nine
town?*, not including Hartford and New Haven.
jive Elaine 24,696, Cleveland 23,236, scattering
9 '..6.M. For Governor, Harrison receives 24,897,
Waller 23.M2, scattering 1,497.
Hartford, November Ith. The Republicans
fain one Congressman, Buck, in the First Dis
trict. Mitchel (D.) in elected in the Second, Sey
mour (D.) in the Third, find Wait (K.) in the
Fourth District. Later returns do not change
the result heretofore indicated in the State.
Cleveland's plurality will probably be 1,500.
I Hartford, November lth. Owing to the
troubles on the wires, due fo the storm, the re
turns come in slowly. Seventy towns give
Blame 2.">,1C7, Cleveland 25,867. GarSeld had
25,840, Hancock 24,623. The Uepublicau loss is
637. The same ratio of loss would give the State
10 Cleveland by a small plurality.
Hartpokp, November ith. Eighty towns give
Blame 39,955, Cleveland 30.822. The same gave
Qarfleld 81,038, Hancock 29,474 a Republican
loss of 3,431. Cleveland undoubtedly curries
the State. Mitchell (D.) is elected to Congress
n the Second District. For Governor, Herrison
has 30,218, Waller 31.242. Scattering 1 .410. Prob
ably there is no election of State officers, and
the Republican Legislature will elect Harrison.
FLORIDA.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045789/1884-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=DOUBT+Demonstrations+Grover+Cleveland+Hendricks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Jay Gould this morning sent the lollow
ing to Governor Cleveland: "I heartily
congratulate you on your election. We all
concede rHew 1 ork. i our Administration
as governor hus been wise and conservative
and in the larger field as president, 1 feel
that you will do still better and tho vast
business interests of the country will be en
tirely safe in your hands."
Sighed: Jay Goixn.</text>
      </result>


      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042460/1884-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Cock+Crows+Cleveland+Grover+Election+Hendricks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE ELECTION.
Cleveland will Occupy the
presidential Mansion.
OIR ROOSTKRS I'ltoi 01.Y4 ROW.
Tin* Cry of Fraud Raised in New
York. Bat the Demoeratn will
Kiitifv .fust the Snme—
Hurrah for Cleveland!
\Sperhil to thf HrniM h'l A iMoei.ft ft Prr**.
Hew York.
Nkw York, Nov. ?.—On ft careful review
of the figures by districts as furnished by
agents of the Associated Preu, corrected by
PtlOrni received during the day so as to
bring the record down this time.
The vote Of the Htate stand*: For
Cleveland. 98t,M»; Blame, .W,*j6, a
plurality for Cleveland of iw There »rt»
yet 1* districts from which returns arc still
behind or questioned The«c hi IssiK'ive
Uarfleld a plurality off 7M. The counties In
which thf lacking di-trietsnre situated are
Warn** m I'll— ii Saratoga. Sullivan and
I'lstcr.
Inn thr Krpubllran t ommKln
Snya.</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014381/1884-11-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Latest+Election+Grover+Cleveland+Presidential+Hendricks</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LATEST ELECTION NEWS.
[SPECIAL DIS, ATCHRS TO the RECORD- UNION.]
THE OFFICIAL CANVASS IX XEW YORK.
New York. November 13th. total
vote of. Brooklyn, as. officially announced
to-day. gives Cleveland a plurality of 15,
--7*52, being a gain of six for Cleveland.
Broome county: Blame, 7,182; Cleve
land, 5,7.0; St. John, 458; Butler. 144.
Wyoming county: Blame, 4.441 Cleve
land, 3,189; St. John, 483; Butler, 53.
Otsego connty Cleveland, 7,307 Blame,
6,671. Butler. 81 St. John, 432.
_•, Schuyler county Blame. 2,016; Cleve
land, 2,039; St. John, 154; Butler, 111.
Orange county Republican Electors, 9,-
IXiS twenty-eight Democratic Electors, 9,-
S4l each two, 9,840; four, 9,838; one. 9,837
St. John Electors, 6l7 Butler Electors. 175.
Chenango county: Blame, 5,462; Cleve
land, 4,410; St. John, 506; Butler, 334.
Sullivan county: Blame. 3,332; Clove
land, 3,607; St John, 183; Butler, 232.
Oneida county Cleveland, 13.820; Blame,
13,790 Cleveland's plurality. 30 St. John,
894; Butler, 189. -j-"..;'
The St. Lawrence County Canvassers were
in session part of Tuesday and all day yes
terday, but hive not completed the canvass,
owing to clerical errors in the returns of
several districts, which will not affect the
result. Tbe canvass will show Blame, 13,
--441; Cleveland, [6,035; St. John, 311 But
ler, 20.
Columbia county: Blame, 6,424; Cleve
land, 5.851; Butler.".;; St. John, 168.
Albany connty: Cleveland 18,345, Blame
17.698, St. John: 312, Butler 983.
Delaware county: Blame 5,934, Cleveland
1,956, St. John 437, Duller 112.
New York, November 13th. The vote
On the Presidential ticket canvassed by the
Board of Canvassers is as follows: First
Assembly District (fourth election district
missing) Blame 2,231, Cleveland 4,265,
Butler '.'_. St. John 15. Second Assembly
District— 2.130. Cleveland 5,239,
Butler 94, St. John 8. Third Assembly Dis-
Blame 2,624, Cleveland 5,111, Butler
126, St. John 11 Fourth Assembly Dis-
Blame 2,391. Cleveland 0,322, Butler
158, St. John 10. Fifth Assembly District—
Blame 2,605, Cleveland 4,508, Butler 125.
St. John 17. Sixtii Assembly District—
Blame 2,650, Cleveland 5,612, Butler 126,
St. John 5. Seventh Assembly District
(two election districts missing) Blame
1,653, Cleveland 4,242, Butler 88, St. John
74. Eighth Assembly District— 4,722,
Cleveland 4,140, Butler 09, St. John 10.
THE METROPOLIS.
New York, November 13th. The gains
and losses in the returns of the Board of
Canvassers, so far as the canvass has been
made, as compared with the press returns
sent out on election night, are as follows:
First Assembly District, Third Election
District, Blame gains 10 votes; Seventh
Assembly District, Tliird Election District,
Cleveland gains 3 votes; Twelfth Election
District Cleveland gains lA*6tc; Fifteenth
Election District, Cleveland loses 1 vote;
Seventeenth Election District' Blame gains
78 votes and Cleveland loses 155 votes;
Third Assembly District, Sixteenth Elec
tion District, Cleveland loses 2 votes;
Twenty-first Election District. Cleveland
gains 2 votes Twenty-third Election Dis
trict, Cleveland gains I vote: Twenty-sixth
Flection District, Blame loses 3 votes;
Fourth Assembly District, Twelfth Election
District, Cleveland loses 10 votes; Twenty
first Election District, Blame gains 1 vote.
DEJIOCRATIC FK-IRES.
New York, November 13th. The otli
eial canvass of the vole received at the
headquarters of the Democratic State
Committee to-day from various points in
the State is as follows: Delaware county,
Blame's plurality, 978; Columbia county,
Blame's plurality, 510; Rockland county,
Cleveland plurality. 1,104; Schoharie coun
ty, Cleveland's plurality, 1,807: Kings coun
ty, Cleveland's plurality, 15,734; Broome
county, Blame's plurality, 1,402; Schuyler
county, Blame's plurality, .".77: Franklin
county, Blame's plurality, 1,090; Oneida
county, Cleveland's plurality, 30.
THE "lIERALII's'* SUJIMARY.
New York, November 13th. The Herald,
in i:- summary, says The vote of New
York Stale by counties, as far as ascer
tained by Official count, gives Cleveland a
plurality of 1.254 votes. In the ca_e of six
counties, however, where tbe canvassers
adjourned ing to some technicality, and
where the pluralities nay be changed; un
official figures are given. The votes for
Bulk*!* aid bt. John are as follows: St.
John, 22,739 Butler, 12,539. In the coun
ties already canvassed there has been no
material change in majorities since yester
day. Blame has lined one vote in Colum
bia and two in St. Lawrence county, and
lost two vol in Schuyler; making his net
gain one vote. Cleveland lias gained six
votes in Kings and i- sl ten in Oneida, mak"
ing bis net loss four votes. This reduces
Cleveland's plurality by five votes, making
it now 1,254. Only Ihreeeounties have not
vet furnished the official result— Franklin.
Greene and New York.</text>
      </result>



      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1884-11-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=OVER+Election+Grover+Cleveland+Hendricks+President+Presidential</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>First election di trict eighteenth as
rcnablv district by an error returned
1 votes to the Blaine electors The
number should hayebeejn 81 The c onr
niittee on corrections will rectify1 thb
error and report in favor of 81 votes on
Monday morning With that return i
the official vote of the lowest Demo
cratic elector in this city is 133157 nnd
for the highest Republican etector f 03
giving the lowest Cleveland elect or a
plurality of 43044
The following are the official and
complete figures in the assembly dis
trict named
Seventh Blaine 4882 Cleveland 4620
Butler 106 St John 78
Ninth Blaine 4581 Cleveland 5273
Butler 125 St John 124
Thirteenth Blaine 4876 Cleveland
4459 Butler 131 St John 100
The Fifteenth assembly district com
plete gives Blaine 4172 Cleveland 0446 I
Du tier 215 St John 44
The Sixteenth assembly district com
plete gives Blaine 2718 Cleveland 5319
Butler 167 St John 17
The Seventeenth assembly district
complete gives Blaine 5265 Cleveland
fi395 Butler 214 St John 59
Eighteenth assembly district com
plete gives Blaine 2785 Cleveland 6253
Butler 209 St John 25
Nineteenth assembly district com
plete gives Blaine 4580 Cleveland 6580
Butler 162 St John 56
Twentieth assembly distriQtwcom
rlete Blaine 3436 Cleveland 6016 But
ler 155 St John 8
Twentyfirst assembly district com
plete Blaine 4080 Cleveland 4640 But
ler 53 St John 59
Twentysecond assembly district
complete Claine 5341 Cleveland 9104
Butler 234 St John 64
s
Twentythird assembly district eom
plete Blaine 723V Cleveland 8842 But
ler 293 St John 132
The returns of th Twent second as
sembly district were canvassed without
change There were ten defective and
seven blank votes
The returns of the Twentythird as
sembly district were canvassed without
change
Twentyfourth jvHernbly district i
complete Blaine IjJLi Cleveland 5309
Butler 142 St Johif</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
